hello and welcome to BQ Prime you're
watching earnings with VQ and our guest
today is Mr gopal balachandran the CFO
and cro of ICICI Lombard General
Insurance the company came out with its
results uh yesterday evening and its net
profit is up 12 and net premiums earned
are also up 12 uh its overall revenue is
up around 14 let's hear it from Sir on
how they've done this quota welcome to
the show sir yeah good morning everyone
and uh welcome to all your viewers
your profit Rose 12 and um overall you
know but but sequentially it is down 11
I know I know as an insurance company
you don't have to really look at it
sequentially but just trying to
understand that is there some element of
the Cyclone effect which has kind of
impacted the net profit this quarter or
is there something else which is
impacting the sequential profits so
that's definitely a great question and
uh as you rightly said uh the insurance
business is all about cycles and hence
to that extent uh there's a lot of
things that go into a quarterly numbers
and hence and that's why we always keep
urging to ideally look at numbers over
periods over three to five years
definitely not on a quarter on quarter
basis if at all you have to look at it
look at it more on an annual cycle at
least at the minimum but ideally over
three to five years is what one would
urge to look at the numbers but having
said that to answer your point in terms
of how to how do we see the q1 numbers
play out for us I think we are very
excited and happy with the way how
things have progressed and the reason
why we say this is uh I think clearly
let's say from a growth standpoint we
have had an industry beating number an
industry group roughly about 17.9
percent is shared lower than 18. our
growth at an aggregate level was one
percent higher than the market and
almost 18.9 so clearly we had an out
performance in terms of growth and in
line with the current accounting
stipulations whenever you see periods of
high growth the relative cost of
acquisition that you have to incur for
sourcing the businesses they comes in
they come and hit you after it ah so
which is why from an absolute
underwriting or let's say from an
absolute profit numbers you would
possibly see an expense strain because
the earnings of the growth that you have
exhibited tends to play out over the
contract period or let's say over the 12
month cycle whereas the cost is hitting
you on day one at the time when you are
sourcing the risk so which is why when
you look at the numbers on an absolute
basis whether you look at it year on
year or sequentially whichever way you
look at it uh this you need to kind of
factor in for this impact exactly for
this reason is why you need to kind of
that gets largely adjusted when you look
at the combined ratio numbers and which
is where you would see for us for Isis
lumbar the combined ratios for quarter
one has been better at 103.8 percent uh
this number if you looked at quarter one
of last year was it about 104.1 and even
when you look at let's say for quarter
four of last year that number was
slightly higher than 104. 104 plus so
clearly directionally I think
sequentially or year on year whichever
way you look at it we have actually seen
an improvement in the overall combined
ratio and two to your point yes the
absolute profit also does get impacted
by some of the losses from the Cyclone
events that we have seen in q1 last year
q1 thankfully we didn't have any of
major events play out but this year of
course Cyclone before Joy has had an
impact which is the number that we also
put out as a part of the deck we had a
net claim impact of almost about 35
crores roughly about 380 claims that we
had on account of cyclone before Joy the
good news is as a company for Isis
number we have been very very proactive
in uh claim settlements so while I said
on the Cyclone we had almost lost about
380 cases more than 70 percent of those
claims have already been settled so
which also results let's say into an
outflow and that's also getting
exhibited in the absolute amount of
profit numbers that you spoke about but
as I mentioned directionally if I were
to exclude the impact of cyclone losses
from the ratio numbers of 103.8 it our
reported combined would have been
actually 102.9
okay
so then then we can say we are inching
towards very close to the goal that
you've set for fy25
yeah I think that's uh directionally
that is what we had spoken even earlier
I think uh last year fy23 as I said full
year we ended the book with this number
slightly higher than 104 and
directionally we had said as you
mentioned over the next two years which
is End by end of F525 is when we would
want to see the combined about at about
102 so directionally that is the
trajectory that we want to take and uh
hopefully I think we are kind of pretty
much on track to achieve that having
said that I would only kind of carry it
to say that we obviously will have to
wait and see how some of the other
catastrophic events play out because
already we have seen let's say again in
Q2 there have been significant flooding
which has happened in North India too
early for us to really see how the
impact will play out early days I mean
claims are getting trickled in but
having said that we
Will Wait of an impact as some of these
events happen
so what is the kind of growth that
you're in searching for the whole year
holier than one percent
in you what are you picking it at
so let me put that in the context of uh
the pillars that uh Isis Lombard has in
terms of its positioning to capture the
opportunity of growth now let me put at
a macro level first if you look at the
macro level my market share is at about
8.3 as a company so therefore there is
enough and more Headroom that's
available for us to kind of uh grow the
business now within that if you look at
what are the key levers which will help
us drive that I mean clearly we have the
distribution strength to our advantage
we have been kind of significantly
investing in technology at scale which
will help us drive efficiency and
productivity in terms of operations
and three as a company we have been very
very proactive in significantly
investing on claim service and that's
the reason why when you look at our net
promoter scores you look at our the the
number the time that we take to settle
claims etc etc all of them have been
kind of significantly positive so all
the right pillars is something that we
have always had in order to drive growth
it's just that at times certain segments
markets tends to get very very
aggressive in terms of pricing and
therefore consciously we kind of
calibrate some of the growth in some of
the segments where the markets are very
very aggressive now at this point of
time as I mentioned q1 we have been able
to kind of beat the industry growth
going ahead assuming the market
continues to remain sensible then our
expectation has always been to have at
least one to two percent uh growth
numbers higher than the market growth uh
percentages that's the thought process
and the reason why we believe this is
possible is because the regulator is now
put in place a new expensive management
guideline that is effective from April
23 and while we have the full year
numbers for every player in the market
so when you look at the expensive
management for the market as a whole
almost two-thirds of the market uh or
two-thirds of the non-life industry
players are having an expensive
management higher than the threshold now
clearly the regulator has also said each
of these companies will have to bring
down their expensive management numbers
below 30 percent so that's again it's an
opportunity as the player starts to kind
of work on this path it again presents
it presents us an opportunity for growth
which is what I said we would obviously
want to see at least one to two
percentage points higher than the
industry programs
I understand you all are at 26.6 percent
eom
so there's still a Headroom until 30
percent absolutely absolutely is that
the company we have always been kind of
operating at a threshold which is well
below the expense of management
guideline and as as I said if players
starts to further work on bringing down
their expensive management then the
focus becomes more on service and and
distribution where clearly ICC Lombard
has the inherent advantage
so now when you have that sort of
Headroom I understand that uh the
company was very interested in uh in
penetrating further in the motor
insurance space so what is happening
there I mean of course compared to last
year your motor insurance operating
profits are at least doubled so um are
we putting in more resources towards
that particular segment uh what are what
are the categories where also our
premiums have gone up by 12 so what is
the line of business that is seeing uh
more response versus the other if you
could just give us some idea yeah I
think that's that's a great question uh
so if you ask if you ask us let me put
that in context uh I think over the last
couple of years as I said the market in
motor particularly has been very very
aggressive and that's evident from the
industry combined ratios if you look at
industry combined ratios for first half
of last year that was about 124 if you
look at the second half we had said
there is some bit of easing that we had
seen in the market which is why second
half of the industry combined is 118
percent roughly around that so there has
been some improvement but still it is at
an elevated level and hence to that
extent is where we have been a bit more
guarded in terms of growing our motor
portfolio but the good news is if you
look at for Isis lumbar sequentially I
think we have been able to arrest the
extent of growth that one has seen just
to kind of make my point if you would
have looked at the numbers for the month
of April for motor we had a degrowth in
the month of May we had a positive
growth of almost about six percent for
the month of June we had a growth of
about 11 so sequentially I think we have
enabled
state growth Resurgence can
kind of and within this the growth
growthly emanating from the new Private
Car segment which is where we have been
inherently having a significant strength
in terms of sourcing two wheeler when
you look at the numbers coming in from
the oems as well it Violet indicates a
directionally positive change but it is
still not completely out of the votes
when you look at month-on-month numbers
in terms of two wheeler sales it is
still lower than let's say prepandemic
levels and as and when that comes back
we are rightfully positioned to capture
capture the opportunity even on even in
the two wheeler space personal vehicles
if you look at that particular segment
within motor
right now we are again being a bit more
guarded because even this year which is
for 23 24 there has been no price
increase in motor third party now the
moment there is no price increase then
automatically you have to recalibrate
the approach that you want to take in
writing that particular segment which is
why of the overall motor premiums that
we have sourced the mix of CV for
quarter one stands at about 21 so that's
that's what has kind of aided growth but
the earlier point that I made in terms
of Excellence management trajectory for
the market starting to improve once we
also see that playing out hopefully the
regulator will start looking at each of
the company's post there water one uh
earnings being announced I'm sure the
regulator will kind of want to see that
each player in the market are bringing
down their expensive management so hence
we are rightfully positioned directly
seems to be very very positive and
that's how we are kind of positioning to
capture the opportunity for growth in
water
the question on the premium side where
exactly are you seeing from what segment
are you seeing growth coming in so as I
said the new private car is a segment
where we are really kind of seeing
growth are you saying that only uh the
motor segment is where we're seeing
growth I'm talking about overall lines
say uh fire Marine Commerce well I
thought in the context of motor uh so
maybe let me kind of put it across all
the segments um so let me again put this
in context if you look at as an industry
broadly there are four key lines of
businesses right you have motor you have
health you have commercial lines and you
have crop uh for us
um motor health commercial lines all of
them are preferred segments and which is
why pretty much on the rest of the two
segments which is health and Commercial
lines we have had almost industry
beating numbers almost 2x if you look at
commercial lines for quarter one
industry growth was roughly at about
eight percent we had a growth of almost
about 17
again this is pan across all the
segments of commercial lines whether you
look at fire Marine engineering
liability across segments and we have
been able to continue to accredit market
share on the commercial line Space
Engineering again been a far more uh
significant levels of growth thanks to
the trust that the government has been
making on the infrastructure Investments
and therefore that translates into an
incremental opportunity on Project
insurance so which is why within the
commercial lines the engineering line of
business is doing phenomenally well for
us but as a category I think as I said
we have had almost 2x growth uh in the
commercial line space now let me go to
health health when we talk about largely
we talk about two segments which is the
employer employee or let's say the
corporate health and then if you look at
the other retail Health segment as well
on the employer employee again we have
had 2x growth relative to the market I
mean as a health is a segment uh
industry grew at about roughly of 20 for
us the overall health grew at almost
about 40 percent now if I break down
into the employer employee category that
segment for quarter one grew at almost
about 44 percent now this has been an
all-round beat primarily again because
it has been a growth driven by increase
in price it has been a growth that was
driven by increase in volumes and three
thanks to the market some of the players
have started to get far more sensible
and ends to that extent it has also been
an increase accretion in market share so
that's the reason uh we have seen a
growth of almost about 44 in the
corporate space on retail Health that's
been an area of investment which we have
been doing for the last couple of years
at least uh on a serious basis and that
will be a continuing one again very
happy with the way how the progress of
those Investments have played out
because on retail Health Indemnity we
have all we always had a market share
which was less than three percent the
good news is over the last let's say 9
to 12 months of our investments uh
playing out already we are seeing green
shoots in terms of a market share
improving to 3.1 percent still a long uh
Headroom to kind of catch up but at
least the good news is we are able to
see some of those Investments already
reflecting again in distributing numbers
just on the retail Health again we had
almost about 23 growth in q1 Industry
growth on detail Health was about 18 so
hence it's been an all-ground kind of uh
beat the only segment where we are a bit
guarded as I said has been motored but
there again I think we will wait for how
things play out in terms of the expense
of management guideline uh getting
depleted
now so I have I have two questions to
follow questions on segments so uh if we
look at uh the retail Health segment
it's still under an operating loss now
we had taken a price hike in February if
I'm not wrong so since then it is uh it
was expected that you know the the
losses would narrow further and then you
know we are expecting some profitability
but that hasn't quite panned out in the
first quarter yet also if I were to look
at the group health business which has
shown across phenomenal growth like you
mentioned but uh the losses have widened
I mean over last quarter over like the
June quarter last year it's almost up
four times so what exactly is happening
there why have the losses gone up so
much now with covet behind us and uh
things normalizing this sort of law so
is it that we've underwritten some
businesses uh some really risky
propositions why is it that it's widened
so much I think great observations uh so
honestly I think let me answer the first
one for uh on the retail space uh which
is the uh original point that I
mentioned in terms of the why let's say
the absolute profit numbers would have
grown only at 12 for the company as a
whole when I kind of responded to that I
had said whenever growth comes back you
obviously start to see let's say the
acquisition cost coming and hitting your
friend the same explanation holds true
for retail Health the day because we are
making Investments effectively we are
kind of significantly investing in
increasing our head count which is
employees who are will be engaged in the
health agency distribution is what we
are getting on roles whereas the benefit
in the form of revenues will typically
trickle in over a period of time because
these employees will in turn go to the
market get agents on board who will
start becoming productive and therefore
you will start seeing revenues play out
and that's the reason why when you again
look at it from an absolute outcome from
an underwriting standpoint you will
obviously see let's say numbers far more
elevated and that's the reason why when
we look at the numbers we look at it in
the context of what has been the loss
ratio experience of the book that we are
writing just to kind of make sure that
we are not writing any exactly to your
point on are we really picking up any
riskier segments in the way we are
underwriting the portfolio now there if
you see clearly whether it is quarter
one last year or whether it's a full
year or whether you look at q1 of this
year generally our retail Health loss
ratios have stayed in that range of
about 64-65 percent the range we have
been comfortable writing has been in the
range of 65 to 70 but as of now I think
the numbers that is getting reflected is
at about 64 so hence the underlying risk
that
we are quite okay with what we are
underwriting we are not necessarily
taking any riskier proposition but
purely from an absolute underwriting
outcome the moment you make any
instruments in distribution
the cost hits your front the benefit of
revenues will come through over a period
of time so that's the reason why you
find let's say an absolute underwriting
reflecting an adverse Trend the same let
me now come to corporate Health again
there to your point on are we really
assuming any riskier
underwriting uh honestly not and the
reason why I say that is primarily
because when I said the growth of 44 has
been all round including accretion in
market share some of the uh some of the
market participants in the past had gone
very aggressive in writing this
particular category of business and they
lost a lot of money and clearly now
there has been public circulars issued
by each of these Market participants to
their operating offices to get better on
and writing which means the focus now
starts to shift to service and it also
comes at a price at which we are
comfortable with and that's the reason
why we are continuing to upgrade market
share because Isis number is as a
company has been known significantly for
its claim service capability and we
equally happy with the way at the price
at which we are comfortable in terms of
getting those uh premiums now again a
reflection of the loss ratio of the
corporate health book when you look at
the uh again I will as I keep saying
don't look at quarter numbers but just
for the sake of responding to your point
if you look at q1 numbers of corporate
Health loss ratio that number stands at
about 92 percent this if you look at for
the full year of last year that number
was at about 95 so we actually seen a
decline in the corporate Health loss
ratios relative to what we had seen in
the past full year so and to that extent
we are not necessarily writing anything
uh significantly riskier and again you
are quite uh okay with the range of the
loss ratio experience that we are seeing
seeing in writing this particular book
so if I were to understand this
correctly you expect these widened
losses to smoothen out over the period
of
idly to underwrite this business you
don't really need to incur as much
expense as you need on a retail health
book so the expense logic would not I
think work for the corporate Health
segment absolutely the expense logic
will definitely not work but as I said
on a full year basis when you look at
the numbers the range of the loss ratios
that we are writing are quite
comfortable with that so we are not
necessarily taking any increasing
riskier Exposition exposure exposure in
that segment
so uh one more thing there was a lot of
talk around the hardening of rates on
reinsurance side especially for
commercial lines of business yeah so how
is how is that uh panning out and uh
again on the fire side of things we've
seen the loss ratios well like there's a
loss of 30 over last quarter so uh does
that have anything to do with that um
yeah so again a great observation so uh
so so again uh yes uh so couple of uh
impacts one let me address the uh let's
say the the price change uh point that
we have been talking about even in our
April earnings call we did speak about
this yes uh for the quarter the decline
in pricing has been a single digit
number in the range of five to six
percent uh which is on expected lines uh
so nothing significant in that sense
which is why if you see for fire as a
category for the industry as the growth
has been relatively tepid it has been
roughly about six percent or thereabout
But there again if you see ICC Lombards
growth in fire a line of business we are
we have again grown at almost about 11
10 to 11 in that range now so again we
have been able to kind of upgrade market
share uh in that particular portfolio
but having said that yes there has
equally been an impact of increase in
reinsurance cost and what effectively
happens is again because we are kind of
growing the book The only things will
kind of again come through over a period
of time whereas my cost of reinsurance
that I pay tends to kind of fit me
immediately in quarter one so that
definitely tends to have an impact on my
loss ratio numbers so that is one impact
which will smoother now by the rest of
the year as we head into the full year
numbers and secondly as I mentioned in
q1 we also had impact of cyclone before
joy in both fire and let's say the
engineering line of business which
obviously has seen elevated loss ratios
again when you looked at it relative to
q1 of last year uh so if one was to
exclude the impact of losses of cyclone
before Joy from both the fire
engineering line of businesses my
numbers on the loss ratio will look far
more better and it is which will be
pretty much on lines that we are kind of
quite comfortable with so so hence both
impact of reinsurance cost that has set
us in q1 which will smoother out by the
rest of the year and two the impact of
cyclone which also tends to have an
impact in the period whenever the
Cyclones it hit the market
so my last question again uh since we
couldn't get a number on the growth side
if you could give us the number of the
growth that you're envisaging for the
year also now
um some ballpark range in terms of which
you expect to grow on the patch side
because this here is going to be an
abnormal year in terms of because the
cyclone and now the flooding and there
was a lot of talk about El Nino so how
do you see this here as a whole with the
FI 24. so let me address the last part
first which is the threat of El Nino uh
threat of El Nino tends to also have an
impact on one of the lines of businesses
which we didn't pick much which is crop
uh so crop as a portfolio our view is
something that we've always talked about
uh in terms of the overall full year
annual revenues we expect crop to be
less than five percent of the overall
mix to that extent again whatever we are
looking at writing will be extremely
calibrated and as we speak currently we
have an exposure only in Maharashtra and
that again is is under the 1810 scheme
which is operating which is a particular
risk Corridor so hence to that extent we
are again taking a calibrated call and
as I mentioned on a full year Revenue
basis exposure to crop will be less than
five percent of the overall revenues uh
so and primarily exactly also for the
reason that this could be a year of
potential LNO now coming back to your
couple of other points in terms of what
could be the growth percentage and in
terms of revenues as well as in terms of
profit growth honestly as I think as as
we keep saying for Isis number the
market share is 8.3 percent uh there is
enough and more Headroom that's
available for us to grow and we have all
the right levers to kind of capitalize
the opportunity the way we would look at
is I say as we keep saying to kind of
outperform the market buy that 100 to
200 basis points now how much that
growth the market delivers I think we we
would obviously want to see us out
growing the uh industry as a whole
because let's take commercial lines the
government is significantly putting a
lot of thrust on infrastructure I mean
that's a huge opportunity so the market
will grow within that I think we are
better place to capture the opportunity
so hence we would look for an out
performance similarly on health thanks
to covid there has been a continued
demand for let's say having a health
insurance covered so hence and that's
again kind of playing out very well in
line with what I just mentioned so there
again we would obviously want to look at
uh beating the industry numbers retail
health or Investments are again kind of
starting to kind of reflect better
growth outcomes so we would obviously
want to grow continue to grow faster
than the market so rather than giving a
particular
a particular percentage of growth to
kind of work on rather we would look at
us relatively growing better than the
industry in so far as revenues are
concerned now to your point on what does
this translate into profits again it
will be a function of what that growth
number is the more you are able to grow
faster to that external it will tend to
have an impact on my absolute amount of
profits because my cost will come and
hit me a print and a large part of my
business today roughly about 70 75
percent of business is retail so
therefore which relatively tends to have
a slightly higher cost of acquisition
compared to the commercial line of
business friends my cost will come and
hit me up front which is why what we
have spoken about is when you looked at
let's say for fi 23 when we kind of
ended with about 104 combined our return
on Equity was roughly at about close to
16 17 and what we had what we have been
telling the market is Once by F525 and
we want to get get to that combined of
102. that should roughly translate to an
ROV in that range of 18 to 20 percent
now that's what you would kind of
largely look at because an absolute
amount of fat again is a function of
what kind of growth that we see and
therefore it could tend to have an
element of an expense strain that can
come and hit a suffering because the
revenues will get over earned over a
period of time
for the first quarter was around 15 so
you expect that to inch up to 18 to 19
by the end of the year is it I think uh
as I think honestly uh the range that we
would want to kind of get to is to that
range of 18 to 20 over the period by
Enterprise okay bye F5 perfect
thank you so much so it was a pleasure
chatting with you would love to connect
with you again see you next quarter or
even we are open for a chat in the you
know anytime during this quarter as well
yeah sure thank you so much and have a
good day thank you bye
[Music]